Guide to the Accounts and publications about Indians,1934-1938.
Accounts and publications about Indians,1934-1938
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Accounts and publications about Indians, 1934-1938.
9087
Arthur, Roeder
14 folders.
Correspondence, manuscripts, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, biographies, and accounts collected in the 1930s, but describing actions from many years previous. Focus is on western Indians, exploration, and pioneers, particularly pertaining to Colorado and Utah. Folder 1: correspondence from Thomas P. Willson of the society. Stories of Indian captivities in Nebraska. Folder 2: accounts about Tascosa Texas, Guatemala, Central America Accounts, E. B. Sopris, William Carroll Riggs, St. Louis, Pierre Laclede, William Campbell, The Pony Express, J. A. Billington, Thomas P. Wilson, Joseph McCoy, Theodore C. Henry, Mexico, Truman Blancett, Sand and Midway Island in the Pacific, Indian medicine balls, and correspondence written by William E. Drisdale, Jerry Hammer, Mrs. W. W. Boyle, and W. H. Streeper. Folder 3: Account about Indians by the government scout who captured Geronimo, recorded by Morris S. Swett, librarian at Fort Sill Oklahoma. Scout was a Kiowa named I-See-O. Includes excerpts of letters to E. H. Plummer from Hugh L. Scott and notes on the history of Indian use of peyote. Folder 4: Autobiography of Thales H. Haskell. Includes experiences with Indians, Navajo, Ute and others, on a trip out west.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, biographies, and accounts collected in the 1930s, but describing actions from many years previous. Focus is on western Indians, exploration, and pioneers, particularly pertaining to Colorado and Utah. Folder 1: correspondence from Thomas P. Willson of the society. Stories of Indian captivities in Nebraska. Folder 2: accounts about Tascosa Texas, Guatemala, Central America Accounts, E. B. Sopris, William Carroll Riggs, St. Louis, Pierre Laclede, William Campbell, The Pony Express, J. A. Billington, Thomas P. Wilson, Joseph McCoy, Theodore C. Henry, Mexico, Truman Blancett, Sand and Midway Island in the Pacific, Indian medicine balls, and correspondence written by William E. Drisdale, Jerry Hammer, Mrs. W. W. Boyle, and W. H. Streeper. Folder 3: Account about Indians by the government scout who captured Geronimo, recorded by Morris S. Swett, librarian at Fort Sill Oklahoma. Scout was a Kiowa named I-See-O. Includes excerpts of letters to E. H. Plummer from Hugh L. Scott and notes on the history of Indian use of peyote. Folder 4: Autobiography of Thales H. Haskell. Includes experiences with Indians, Navajo, Ute and others, on a trip out west.
Folder 5: Correspondence from Thomas P. Wilson and Charles Kelly about the Mormon State of Deseret or Utah. Includes manuscripts written in the Deseret Alphabet by Thales H. Haskell, and E. K. Friller. Discussion of Deseret gold coins, Moquis Indians, Mormons, Joseph Smith and Brigham Young. Also a Photostat of a page from Ordinances of the State of Deseret. Folder 6: Flyer from Las Vegas dated March 24, 1882, titled Notice to thieves, thugs, fakirs, and bunko-steerers. Lists criminals and notes that they will be invited to a "grand neck tie party" if they do not leave town by 10:00pm that night. Criminals listed include, J.J. Harlin, aka Off Wheeler, Saw Dust Charlie, William Hedges, William Henry Bonney, aka Billy the Kid, Billy Mullin, Little Jack, The Cutter, and Pock-Marked Kid. Poster reproduced by the C. S. Card Iron Works Company, Denver. Folder 7: Map of Jefferson Territory and a Photostat of a proclamation, dated June 6, 1861, by R. W. Steele governor of Jefferson Territory disbanding the territory and telling employees and residence to abide by the laws governing the United States. Folder 8: Information about Egyptians and Egypt, particularly King Tutankhamen by Howard Carter and Arthur Weigall excerpted from publications.
Folder 9: Minnequa Historical Society bulletins, 1934. Includes a photo of an old Spanish fort. Information about Indian arrowheads, the Oregon Trail, the Aztecs, information pertaining to the exploration of Colorado and Utah. Folder 10: Minnequa Historical Society bulletins, February through December 1935. Wide range of accounts and information about exploration and life of pioneers and Indians, description of places and forts, in the West, mainly Utah and Colorado. Includes some photos and postcards. Folder 11: Issues of the Minnequa Historical Society bulletins, 1936. These include accounts of pioneer life and Indians of the West. Information on Chief Crazy Horse, Jack Stilwell, Zebulon Montgomery Pike, and Pueblo and Lakota Indians. Folder 12: Various papers about Indians. Correspondence from T. P. Wilson, Margaret Burke, Andrew Jenson, and M. M. Watson. Photo of a Navajo family, information about Folsom points, legend of Texas about the women in blue, Fort Bernard and Santa Clara Indians. Folder 13: Photos from the Oregon Trail near Guernsey, Wyoming. Possibly photos of a town, possibly a mine, wagon wheel tracks, several photos of the register cliffs and rocks showing the names of the pioneers carved in stone, gravestone of Mary E. Homsley. Names on registers include H. H. Roman, W. E. Conwell, L. Acers, E. S. Pemce, N Shre, J. Foreman, A. Lamb.
Folder 14: Three publications, The Colorado Magazine Volume 7 March 1930 with articles on Bent's Fort and Indians in Colorado; Pioneer Days in the Arkansas Valley in Southern Colorado and History of Bent's Fort by Charles Livingstone Seeley, August 1932; and Historical Sketch of Louisiana and the Louisiana Purchase by Frank Bond and the Department of the Interior, 1933.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Roeder, Arthur,; Billington, J. A.; Billy,; Blancett, Truman.; Bond, Frank, 1856-1940.; Burke, Margaret, fl. 1933.; Campbell, William, 1842-1932.; Carter, Howard, 1874-1939.; Crazy Horse, ca. 1842-1877.; Drisdale, William E.; Friller, E. K.; Geronimo, 1829-1909.; Hammer, Jerry.; Harlin, J. J.; Haskell, Thales H.; Hedges, William, fl. 1882.; Henry, Theodore, C.; I-See-O,. 1927.; Jenson, Andrew, 1850-1941.; Kelly, Charles, 1889-; Laclède-Liguest, Pierre de, 1724-1778.; Little Jack.; McCoy, Joseph G.(Joseph Geiting), 1837-1915.; Mullin, Billy.; Pike, Zebulon, 1751-1834.; Plummer, E. H.; Pock-Marked Kid.; Riggs, William Carroll, 1856-1924.; Saw Dust Charlie.; Scott, Hugh Lenox, 1853-1934.; Seeley, Charles Livingstone.; Smith, Joseph, 1805-1844.; Sopris, E. B.; Steele, Robert W.(Robert Wilbur), 1819-1891.; Stilwell, Jack.; Streeper, W. H.; The Cutter.; Tutankhamen,; Tutankhamen, --Tomb.; Watson, M. M.; Weigall, Arthur Edward Pearse Brome, 1880-1934.; Wilson, Thomas P., fl. 1936.; Young, Brigham, 1801-1877.; Roeder, Harriet A.; Huntington Free Library.
Subjects:
Indians of North America.; Indians of North America--Implements.; Indians of North America--Medicine.; Indians of North America--Nebraska.; Indians of Central America--Guatemala.; Indians of Mexico.; Apache Indians.; Aztecs.; Folsom points.; Frontier and pioneer life.; Frontier and pioneer life--Colorado.; Hopi Indians.; Indian captivities.; Kiowa Apache Indians.; Louisiana Purchase.; Mormon Church.; Mormon pioneers.; Mormons.; Navajo Indians.; Peyote.; Pioneers.; Pony express.; Pueblo Indians.; Teton Indians.; Ute Indians.
Places:
Arkansas River Valley--History.; Bent's Fort (Colo.); Deseret.; Guernsey (Wyo.); Louisiana--Boundaries.; Louisiana--History.; Midway Islands.; Oregon National Historic Trail.; Pueblo (Colo.); Rose Atoll (American Samoa).; Tascosa (Tex.); Trinidad (Colo.); Utah.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Accounts, biographies, and correspondence
Folders 1-4
Series II. Published items
Folders 5-8, 12, 14
Series III. Minnequa Historical Society bulletins
Folders 9-11
Series IV. Photographs
Folder 13
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Accounts, biographies, and correspondence
  - Captivities (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Laura L. Roper
  - Accounts (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - William E. Drisdale
    - Jerry Hammer
    - General E. B. Sopris
    - W. W. Boyle
    - William Carroll Riggs
    - Thomas P. Wilson
    - William Campbell
    - J. A. Bullington
    - W. H. Streeper
    - Trumon Blancett
    - Mrs. George B. Perry
  - I-See-O, Kiowa Indian scout (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Thales H. Haskell (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Series II. Published items
  - Ordinances of the State of the Dessert (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Dessert Alphabet
    - Thales H. Haskell
      Includes note from B. W. Harrison 1934 stating that letter in the alphabet written by his father, Haskell, when he and E. K. Friller were with the missionairies with the Moquis Indians during the Winter of 1859-1860.
  - Notice flyer for "Grand Neck-tie Party", hanging (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Proclamation disbanding territory of Jefferson with map (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - King Tutankhamen (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Misc. articles photos, clippings (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Pioneer Days in the Arkansas Valley in Southern Colorado and History of Bent's Fort Charles Livingstone Seeley, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Historical Sketch of Louisiana and the Louisiana Purchase Frank Bond, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - The Colorado Magazine State Historical Society of Colorado, March, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Series III. Minnequa Historical Society bulletins
  - August, October, Christmas 1934 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - February-December 1935 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - February 1936 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Oregon Trail (Box 14, Folder 13)